

Subhransu Maharana

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

Full Stack Engineer



+91 9886326216



subhransumaharana@gmail.com



https://subhnet.github.io



https://www.linkedin.com/in/smaharana



ABOUT ME

An Experienced Full-Stack Developer with 7+ years of experience in designing, developing and implementing applications and solutions using range of technologies. Always keen to learn new technologies, Following best Quality Practices by applying Design Patterns, on-time Delivery.



WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Engineer

Adobe

Jun 2019- Present (2 years 7 months +)

- Worked on building executive-focused Adobe analytics dashboards for Adobe's top digital marketing clients and developing custom web applications end to end to solve various customer needs.
- Designed and Developed an Automation Framework that automates the process of onboarding a client to Adobe Analytics, Launch, and Target for a Customer Website.
 This Framework has reduced the Consultant Efforts significantly by 90% and is now used across other teams.
- Developing serverless and event-driven applications based on events originating from various Adobe services using **Adobe I/O runtime**, events.
- Responsible for building automation tools for AEM CM deployment using Gulp Scripts, Github API, Github Actions, which enabled my teammates to significantly reduce the development effort.
- Creation of Big Data Pipelines in Spark on AWS
- Migrating leagacy Apache ETL process to WFE (Apache Airflow) for scaling and processing higher volumes of data
- Data Reprocessing for billions of records to cleanse the data in Adobe Analytics
- Worked with tight deadlines and small consulting budgets to complete major tasks.

Server Side: **Node.js**, **Express.js**, Java, Docker, AWS, GraphQL, Apache Openwhisk, Python, pySpark, Kafka

Client Side: ReactJS, Javascript, HTML, CSS

Software Engineer

Mar 2017- May 2019 (2 years 3 months)

Fidelity Investments

- Responsible for upgrading the codebase to Angular UI and Back-end in JAVA SpringBoot Restful Services. Develop testable, reusable, and maintainable components/services, integrating Restful APIs.
- Responsible for building a Table Component Framework for eTax Application, which
 made dynamic content to be easily customizable, focusing on its stability. It was
 reused across Multiple teams as well.
- Implemented Lazy-Loading, leading to an 85% reduction in web app loading time.
- Identified and suggested new technologies and tools for enhancing product value

Project Engineer

Sep 2014- Feb 2017 (2 years 6 months)

Wipro Technologies

Bluedart Website Revamp

• Key Contributor in development and implementation of the project from build-out testing and integration into the production environment.



SKILLS

FRONT END

- ReactJS, AngularJS (4.4)
- HTML5, CSS
- Javascript(ES6)
- Typescript
- JQuery

BACK END

- Java
- Node.JS, ExpressJs
- Python, pandas framework
- Spring Framework
- SpringBoot
- MySQL
- Serverless Framework

DEVOPS

- AWS, Azure
- Docker
- Apache Openwhisk
- Apache Airflow
- Github Actions

MISCELLANEOUS SKILLS

GraphQL Gulp Git Tomcat NGINX Maven Webpack Babel Rest API, Adobe I/O



ACHIEVEMENTS

- "On the Spot Award" Awarded in Fidelity Investments, 2017.
- "Individual Award" Awarded for solving complex framework bugs in Fidelity, 2018.
- "Team of the Quarter" Awarded for contribution in Adobe, 2020
- Selected for "Adobe Tech Summit'21"
- Certified in "Azure Fundamentals AZ-900"



EDUCATION

B.Tech, Computer Science Veer Surendra Sai University of Technology, Burla, Odisha 2010-2014